https://www.patagonia.com/privacy-policy.html

Shop Food
.
Shop Food
.
Effective date: July 1, 2020
This policy describes how Patagonia, Inc. and its parent, subsidiary, and affiliate companies (collectively, “Patagonia,” “we,” or “us”) collect, use and share information collected through the mail, Patagonia retail stores and wholesale accounts, Patagonia.com and other websites that link to this privacy policy, and Patagonia mobile services including our mobile application (the “App”) (collectively, the “Patagonia Services”).
HOW WE COLLECT AND USE INFORMATION
Data and Personal Information (“PI”)
We or our vendors may collect data and/or personal information (“PI”) such as your name, your contact information, your shipping information, and your billing information (such as credit card account data). We collect PI when you provide it to us through your use of the Patagonia Services, for example when you interact with our websites, place an order, or sign up for our mailing list. We also receive limited PI when you choose to download or request the App. We may combine the PI we collect with additional information from other third-party sources.
We use the PI that we collect to provide the Patagonia Services (such as to process and ship your orders or respond to customer service requests), to analyze and improve the Patagonia Services, and to conduct marketing. If you register for email or if you provide your email address to us, we will send you emails about a variety of topics such as store events, new products, special sales, promotional offers from our affiliates or other selected business partners, environmental issues, and employment opportunities. Please see below for your choices regarding how we collect, use and share your PI.
We share email activity data with our marketing email provider to help them better target email deployments to consumers. While our marketing email provider has access to email address and email activity and may share bulk/non-specific activity data, no email addresses or specific email actions are ever shared with other third parties. Should a consumer wish to opt out of this sharing, that consumer simply needs to opt out of marketing email from us.
Geographic Location
Our App uses the GPS feature of your mobile device to determine the location of the device. We and our third-party vendors or partners may collect and use this geographic location data for purposes such as the functioning of the App, to make our advertising more relevant, and to improve Patagonia Services. For example, we use the location information to provide the address and directions for the nearest Patagonia retail location. We do not store geographic location data in combination with other PI. If you do not want us or third parties to collect and use your device’s geographic location, you can control this function in your application settings (if your device offers this type of control), by disabling location services for your device, or by uninstalling the App, but these choices will affect your ability to use the App.
Usage Information and Analytics
We automatically collect certain usage information when you use Patagonia Services. For example, we collect information about the devices you use to connect to our services (such as the IP address of your computer or numeric identifier of your mobile device) and about how you use Patagonia Services (such as what time you visit our websites). We, and our advertisers and ad servers, may also collect information outside the Patagonia Services to measure the success of our advertising campaigns. We use the information that we collect for a variety of purposes such as to provide and improve the Patagonia Services, and to analyze and offer our advertising.
Our website also uses third-party analytics vendors such as Google Analytics. Please click here for more information about how data is collected and processed in connection with the Google Analytics service. We and our third-party vendors or partners use analytics data for a variety of purposes such as to improve the design and content of our websites, to help us learn things like what pages are most attractive to all of our visitors and what promotions visitors like to see, and to gauge the success of our advertising campaigns.
Information You PostAll information that you share about yourself, whether of a personal nature or not, in a public open forum – such as on a social network – is likely public information. If you don’t want it to be public, please don’t post it.
HOW WE SHARE INFORMATIONWe do not disclose your PI to third parties, except as follows:
To companies that provide services to us or perform functions on our behalf (such as processing credit card payments or taking orders) and have agreed to use your information only for the purposes we request;
For us to send offers to Patagonia customers on behalf of our affiliated companies and on behalf of other non-affiliated partners (such as environmental groups that we support);
To other selected reputable companies, we may disclose your name and postal address (but not your email address or credit card information) so that they can mail you information that may interest you;
When we believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with applicable law, legal process, and/or governmental authorities;
When we believe disclosure is appropriate to enforce our Terms of Use and other agreements, or to protect our rights, our customers, our property, our employees, or others; and
If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, partial or total sale of assets, or other corporate change.
We may disclose de-identified, aggregated, or other non-personal information to third parties in our discretion. The Patagonia Services or our offerings on social media platforms may include commenting, forums, sharing, or other similar features. Information that you provide using these features may be available to other users or the general public.
YOUR CHOICES
With your PI – like the information you give us to fulfill an order – you have the option to change or correct your information and the choice of not hearing from us again. There are several ways you can control our use of your PII in connection with marketing and promotions.
To remove your name from our lists. You can choose to decline communications from us at the point that we request your PI. After we have collected your PI, you can choose to stop our communications or our service or stop us from sharing your information with other companies for their marketing purposes. To exercise any of these options, please contact us by mail, email, or telephone using the contact information below.
To stop email communications. If you receive email communications from us and want to opt out of receiving such communications in the future, you can click the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the promotional email.
To stop collection of geographic location. If you do not want us to collect your device’s geographic location through our App, you can disable that function when you first use the App or in your device settings. This will prevent you from using some features of the App.
Other choices. Please see below to learn about your choices with regard to our use of cookies and interest-based advertising.
CORRECTING OR UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION
If you would like to request changes to the PI that you have previously provided to us, please contact us by mail, email, or telephone using the contact information below.
COOKIES
We may use “cookies,” “web beacons,” and other similar technologies to collect information in connection with the Patagonia Services and our advertisements. A “cookie” is a computer file that acts as an identification card for your computer to distinguish your browser from others and enable us to serve you better. For example, we use cookies to save products in your shopping cart while you browse our websites and to track the effectiveness of our marketing and advertising campaigns. Similarly, a “web beacon” is a technology that can recognize specific cookies and convey information about that browser. We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests.
Most browsers accept cookies automatically. You may be able to set your browser to reject and/or delete cookies. For instructions, check your browser’s technical information. However, if you reject or delete cookies then this may disable or interfere with features of the Patagonia Services or other websites you visit. We recommend that you leave cookies “turned on” so we can offer you a better shopping experience on our sites.
INTEREST-BASED ADVERTISING
We may work with third-party advertising companies that collect and use information about your online activities across sites over time, in order to deliver more relevant advertising when you are using the Patagonia Services and elsewhere on the Internet. This practice is known as interest-based advertising. You may visit www.aboutads.info to learn more and to opt out of this type of advertising by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance self-regulatory program. We do not operate or control this site and are not responsible for the opt-out choices available there. Note that electing to opt out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. If you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies or use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.
CHILDREN
The online Patagonia Services are not intended for the use of individuals under the age of 16, and we do not knowingly collect information online from individuals under the age of 16.
THIRD PARTIES AND SOCIAL MEDIA
Our websites and App may contain links to third-party online properties. Such third parties have their own policies that govern their collection, use, and disclosure of information. We suggest that you read their privacy policies to learn about their practices.
Social media provides tools that many of our customers use and enjoy, and we include links to various social media platforms on our websites. If you interact with these social media tools through our websites, your experience on those social media sites will be governed by the privacy and other policies of those sites. So, the privacy settings you have chosen on those sites will determine the degree to which your information is made public. We encourage you to choose your privacy settings on those sites accordingly.
SAFEGUARDING YOUR PI
We have reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative measures in place to safeguard the security of your personal information. However, when you communicate with customer service via email or chat on our websites, these communications may not be encrypted. For that reason, we ask that you do not share sensitive information via these communication channels.
YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS
The California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) and, potentially, other applicable state or federal laws provide you with rights regarding how your data or personal information is treated, and we want to ensure you understand and are able to exercise those rights.
Personal Information We Collect, Disclose or Sell for a Business Purpose. The chart below summarizes the categories of personal information we have collected and shared in the past 12 months for a business purpose, and for “sale.” (see last two columns of the table below for a description of each) Please know that the definition of “sale” under CCPA and other laws can be very broad and therefore may include in their scope many common business activities involving the sharing of data, even when the personal information shared is not exchanged for money.
The categories of personal information we collect:
Sources of this personal information:
The purposes why we collect and use this personal information:
Categories of third parties to whom we disclose this personal information:
Categories of third parties to whom we sell this personal information:
Identifiers like your name, email, address, phone number and phone call records, payment information, IP address, cookies
You, when you create an account with us, buy products from us, interact with our customer service department, return products, submit products for repair, sign up for our emails, sign up to receive our catalogs, sticker requests, sign up for our store events or sign up and engage with one of our environmental activism campaigns; your browser or mobile device when you visit our website
To make your brand experience more relevant to you by serving you products, content and environmental and activism initiatives you may be interested in based on your history with us, to create an account for you, to process, fulfill and deliver products, services, and marketing materials to you , to market environmental activism campaigns to you, to provide effective customer service) and to improve our business intelligence; to improve and personalize our website and to market products and services to you that you may be interested in based on your interaction with our website
Service providers for services related to payment processing, data accuracy, fraud detection and security, order processing and management, logistics, shipping, customer relationship management, web and mobile development, email marketing and advertising
Marketing and advertising providers
Commercial information such as purchasing history or tendencies
You, when you buy products from us, returns products or submit products for repair
To make your brand experience more relevant to you by serving you products, content and environmental and activism initiatives you may be interested in based on your history with us, to provide effective customer service and to market products to you that you may be interested in based on your purchasing history with us, to process returns of product and to process repairs for product you submit to us)
Service providers for services related to order processing and management, logistics, shipping, customer relationship management, email marketing and advertising
Marketing and advertising providers
Internet activity information, like browsing history, search history, interactions with our website and online advertisements, user-generated/submitted content
Your browser or mobile device when you visit our website or engage with our online advertisements, or you when you buy or return products from us, submit them for repair, or post or submit content or comment on our social media accounts
To make your brand experience more relevant to you by serving you products, content and environmental and activism initiatives you may be interested in based on your history with us, to improve and personalize our website and to market products and services to you that you may be interested in based on your interaction with our website
Service providers for services related to web and mobile development, email marketing and advertising, services related to order processing and management
Marketing and advertising providers
Geolocation information
Your browser or mobile device when you visit our website
To make your brand experience more relevant to you by serving you products, content and environmental and activism initiatives you may be interested in based on your history with us, to improve and personalize our website, to market products to you that you may be interested in based on your location and interaction with our website, and to estimate for you the timing of shipping/delivery of products
Service providers for services related to web and mobile development, email marketing and advertising, logistics and shipping
Marketing and advertising providers
Professional or employment information included in materials like resumes and cover letters
You, when you apply to a job at Patagonia
To evaluate you for the job opening you applied for
Service providers for services related to human resources information management
None
Inferences we make about you based on the above information to predict your characteristics and preferences
All of the information described above, we also purchase information from credit agencies that may contribute to our inferences about you
To make your brand experience more relevant to you by serving you products, content and environmental and activism initiatives you may be interested in based on your history with us, to improve and personalize our website and retail stores to market products and services to you that you may be interested in based on the inferences we make about you
Service providers for services related to web and mobile development and site personalization, email marketing and advertising
None
Your Rights Regarding Personal Information. You have the following rights with respect to the personal information we collect, subject to certain exceptions and limitations:
For certain categories of personal information, the right to request a list of what personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties;
The right to know the categories and/or specific pieces of personal information we collect, use, disclose, and sell about you, the categories of sources from which we collected your personal information, our purposes for collecting or selling your personal information, the categories of your personal information that we have either sold or disclosed for a business purpose, and the categories of third parties with which we have shared personal information;
The right to request that we delete the personal information we have collected from you or maintain about you.
The right to opt out of our sale of your personal information.
The right not to receive discriminatory treatment for the exercise of your privacy rights under the CCPA.
To exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the following information and submit the required verifying information, as further described below:
By phone at 1-800-638-6464
Online here
Certain Unidentifiable Personal Information. There may be information that is designated as personal information under the CCPA or other state or federal laws, but this information, on its own, does not allow us to identify you in our systems—for example, search or browsing history. If this information is the only information we have collected on you, we will notify you that you are unidentifiable to us – we are not able to find information about you in our systems.
Verification Process and Required Information. We may need to request additional information from you to verify your identity or understand the scope of your request, although you will not be required to create an account with us to submit a request or have it fulfilled. We will require you to provide, at a minimum, your email address, full name, billing address (with zip code) and phone number, and for access requests may require (if you have made a purchase with us) that you identify some items ordered.
Authorized Agent. You may designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, which, for your protection, we will also need to verify as authentic.
UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY
If we modify this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy online. We will notify you if the policy changes in any material way by sending a notice to the email address you provided us or by placing a prominent notice on our website at Patagonia.com. You should check regularly to see if this Privacy Policy has changed.
CONTACT US
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you can email, write, or call us:
Sign up for exclusive offers, original stories, activism awareness, events and more from Patagonia.
Email Address
Subscribe
You’re Signed Up
Track orders, save products, easy hassle-free returns & exchanges. Create a free Patagonia account.
Create an Account
Login to existing account
Get the Beta on Patagonia
Login to existing account
By providing your email address, you agree to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service.
Thanks for joining us,
You can expect to hear from us soon.
Provide your account email address to receive an email to reset your password.
Email
Send
What are you looking for?
Popular searches
